\n# Sheet: 1. Introduction ---
C1: Value: Workbook Contents
L1: Value: Introduction to the MBBR worksheets in this workbook:
A3: Value: Click on tabs at the bottom of the screen to access the following:
L3: Value: Two worksheets are provided to carry out basin sizing and aeration calculations as well as
L4: Value: alkalinity requirements for a Pre-Anoxic Denitrification process and for a Post-Anoxic
B5: Value: Tab 1. Introduction (current tab)
L5: Value: Denitrification process.  The worksheets include calculations for the BOD removal stage
L6: Value: and nitrification stage as well as for the anoxic tank.
B7: Value: Tab 2. Pre-Anoxic Denitrification
L8: Value: Basin sizing is based on a carrier surface area loading rate (SALR).  For BOD removal and
B9: Value: Tab 3. Post-Anoxic Denitrification
L9: Value: denitrification, the design SALR value is selected by the user based on the treatment
L10: Value: objective, (e.g. high rate BOD removal, normal rate BOD removal, or low rate BOD removal.
B11: Value: Tab 4. Derivation of Saturation DO vs T Equation
L11: Value: Typical SALR values are provided on the worksheets.  For nitrification, the design SALR is
L12: Value: calculated from a kinetic model based on the D.O. level to be maintained in the reactor
L13: Value: and the target effluent ammonia nitrogen concentration.
A14: Value: Why you shouldn╞t give copies of this workbook away
A15: Value: We at EngineeringExcelTemplates.com hope that you find this workbook useful. ßIf you
L15: Value: Note that the estimated effluent concentration for BOD, or nitrate nitrogen from each
A16: Value: would like us to develop additional useful spreadsheets for you in the future, then encourage
L16: Value: BOD removal or denitrification stage is calculated by using an estimated value for the
A17: Value: your friends and colleagues to buy their own copies, rather than allowing them to copy
L17: Value: SARR/SALR (surface area removal rate/surface area loading rate).  The estimated value
A18: Value: the spreadsheet you purchased. ßWe have deliberately set our prices so low that no one
L18: Value: for the SARR/SALR is based on an appropriate graph or table from one of the references
A19: Value: can really claim that they can╞t afford to pay. ßBut low prices will work for us∙that is, we
L19: Value: as shown on the worksheets.
A20: Value: can stay in business∙only if we can sell enough copies. ßBottom line: the more you get
A21: Value: other people to pay for their own copies, the more low-cost useful spreadsheets will be
L21: Value: The basin sizing calculations require values for several MBBR carrier properties:  (specific
A22: Value: available for you in the future.
L22: Value: surface area in m2/m3 and % void space).  Values to be used in the design calculations
L23: Value: should come from your carrier supplier.
A24: Value: This workbook is provided "as is", without warranty of any kind, express or
A25: Value: implied.
L25: Value: The aeration/blower calculations are made for a coarse bubble diffuser system.
L26: Value: Coarse bubble diffusers are typically used, because they work better
L27: Value: with the suspended carrier media.
B31: Value:        Find more Excel spreadsheets for engineering at
D32: Value: EngineeringExcelTemplates.com
